Przemyslaw Rudzki

Brampton, 400 Royal West Drive, L6X 5J9

Phone: 416-727-2765 | Email: przemek@rudzki.ca

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rudzki/| GitHub: https://github.com/KiteRunner2 | Portfolio: https://rudzki.ca/portfolio.html

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with a background in telecommunications and architectural design. Experienced professional with first class communication, organization, and administration skills. A talented leader directing highly skilled teams with successes in achieving corporate goals and objectives. Creativity in problem solving and thinking out of the box. Experienced with a fast-paced business environment, projects, and vendor management. Able to learn sophisticated programming skills and write great code from scratch.

KEY SKILLS

Front End:

- ReactJS, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, RESTFul API
- XML, JSON
- Bootstrap, jQuery

Back End:

- Node.js, Express.js
- PHP
- Python

Databases:

• MySQL, MongoDB, Influx

Applications:

• Grafana, Git, Jira, Confluence, Office

Management:

- Project and team management
- Budgeting and budget control
- Agile, Scrum project delivery

CODING PROJECTS

TaskMaster | GitHub: https://github.com/KiteRunner2/TaskMaster | Deploy: https://taskmaster.kiterunner.usermd.net

- TaskMaster is project management tool for teams to organize and share their tasks across the projects
- This was a team project. My responsibility server side: database and sql queries design, server side api calls/routes between client-server-database. Front-end: React components for dashboard, columns, cards including instant updates to database, adding/deleting dashboards, columns, cards. Drag&drop between columns.
- Tools used: Front-end: React.js,JavaScript/jQuery, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap. Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, Multer, bcrypt (password encryption), MongoDB, json.

Hatter (Twitter like clone) | GitHub: https://github.com/KiteRunner2/hatter | Deploy: http://hatter.herokuapp.com/

- Hatter is a chatting application like Twitter. Users can create profiles and follow other users. Create, comment and like posts.
- This was a team project. My responsibility server side: database and sql queries design, server side api calls/routes between client-server-database. Front-end: user interface and logic for creating new messages, comments section, likes.
- Tools used: Front-end: JavaScript/jQuery, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap. Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, Multer, bcrypt (password encryption), MySQL, json.

KPI Dashboard | GitHub: not available due to NDA | Deploy: not available due to NDA

- LTE Network KPI reporting to automate KPI report generation from raw data XML files
- I developed scripts to parse and load data into a database. Designed schemas for more than 1000 counters, built queries/views, connected Grafana to databases and designed queries to visualize data.
- Tools used: Python, MySQL, InfluxDB and Grafana

_

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer Self employed

Nov 2019 - now Brampton, Ontario

I followed my great passion toward programming and changed my career path. I completed the Full Stack Web Developer Certification in university of Toronto. I am currently self-employed building applications for business and individuals *Key accomplishments:*

- Created application for monitoring performance of cellular LTE network. It collects data from raw XML files and visualizes KPIs (key performance indicator) on dashboard. I used Python, MySQL, InfluxDB and Grafana
- Developed website for small businesses (electrician, accountant, food take away)
- Designed and developed trading robots in MQL based on indicators like moving averages, rsi and price patterns

Senior Technical Consultant Asiacell

March 2010 - October 2019

Sulaymaniyah, Iraq

I was CTO consultant for execution of CTIO directives and company's business and technology strategy. Coordinating and preparing annual/3-year budgets in line with shareholder expectations. Enforcing budget control for efficient capex and opex spending. I performed solution analysis, preparations, and execution of multimillion-dollar projects in RAN, Core, Transport.

Key accomplishments:

- Automated Technology Business Unit budget reporting using Python: purchase orders placed, in progress, canceled, etc. It allowed to visualize budget spending and utilization per different categories
- Leading Huawei HLR swap project (migration from standalone solution to geo-redundant pool solution)
- Played vital role in 3G network modernization wide implementation project starting from bid to launch

NSS Manager Monaco Telecom International

May 2007 – March 2010

Dubai, UAE

Supervising team of engineers to make sure that network resources are properly dimensioned and utilized; designing and optimizing core network architecture; following SW/HW upgrades. Played a key role in RFPs and vendor selection process. *Key accomplishments:*

- Successful new HLRs deployment and subscriber migration (swap of Alcatel to Huawei)
- New messaging system implementation (Voice Mail, MCN, Voice SMS) from RFP till commercial launch

Senior System Analyst Proximus (Belgacom Mobile)

January 2007 – May 2007

Brussel, Belgium

I was a part of cross domain functional team tasked to analyze, design, and implement key business projects.

Key accomplishments:

- R4 architecture study leader: Led definition of new architecture for core network with close cooperation of key network vendors, assuring smooth migration from release R99 to R4
- Accurate technical impact analysis on Core network elements for prepaid and postpaid HomeZone project

Core Network Solution Architect

July 1999 – January 2007

Polska Telefonia Cyfrowa Sp. z o.o (mobile operator in Poland)

Warsaw, Poland

I started my carrier as core network specialist and elevate to a technical team lead with multiple direct report. In my role I was responsible for analyzing, testing and introduction of new technologies in core network. I contribute in implementation of major projects such as CAMEL protocol, VPN service, Heyah (sub-brand), 3G network wide Video Call service and received above and beyond recognition.

EDUCATION

- Full time Coding Bootcamp with certification Full stack web developer, University of Toronto
- Military University of Technology in Warsaw, Poland. Profile: electronic and telecommunication.
- Secondary school No. 40 in Warsaw. Profile: math and informatics.